[
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 64,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A strong guard.",
            "job": "To guard.",
            "heal": "Guarded.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "STRO",
            "answer1": "Guarding.",
            "answer2": "Guard",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 64,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A strong guard.",
            "job": "To guard.",
            "heal": "Guarded.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "STRO",
            "answer1": "Guarding.",
            "answer2": "Guard",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 64,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A strong guard.",
            "job": "To guard.",
            "heal": "Guarded.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "STRO",
            "answer1": "Guarding.",
            "answer2": "Guard",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 64,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A strong guard.",
            "job": "To guard.",
            "heal": "Guarded.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "STRO",
            "answer1": "Guarding.",
            "answer2": "Guard",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 64,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A strong guard.",
            "job": "To guard.",
            "heal": "Guarded.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "STRO",
            "answer1": "Guarding.",
            "answer2": "Guard",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 64,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A strong guard.",
            "job": "To guard.",
            "heal": "Guarded.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "STRO",
            "answer1": "Guarding.",
            "answer2": "Guard",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Quix",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A wandering mage",
            "job": "I seek the skeleton!",
            "heal": "Adequate.",
            "keyword1": "SKEL",
            "keyword2": "SECR",
            "answer1": "It knows a great secret.",
            "answer2": "About the purple stone of honor!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have the purple stone?",
            "yesanswer": "Use it wisely!",
            "noanswer": "Seek it for it is very useful!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A big guard.",
            "job": "We guard the gate.",
            "heal": "Excellent.",
            "keyword1": "GATE",
            "keyword2": "GUAR",
            "answer1": "Into and out of Trinsic.",
            "answer2": "'tis an honorable job!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou strive to bring honor upon the peers?",
            "yesanswer": "Dupre, the leader of our towne, joins many honorable quests!",
            "noanswer": "Dolt."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A big guard.",
            "job": "We guard the gate.",
            "heal": "Excellent.",
            "keyword1": "GATE",
            "keyword2": "GUAR",
            "answer1": "Into and out of Trinsic.",
            "answer2": "'tis an honorable job!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou strive to bring honor upon the peers?",
            "yesanswer": "Dupre, the leader of our towne, joins many honorable quests!",
            "noanswer": "Dolt."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Dergin",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A soulful fighter.",
            "job": "I seek a place to rest.",
            "heal": "Tired.",
            "keyword1": "REST",
            "keyword2": "QUES",
            "answer1": "I have quested long and hard.",
            "answer2": "I seek enlightenment at the shrine of honor!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou enlightened in honor?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "The shrine lies to the south and west beyond the swamps!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 42,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Lexington",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A shining paladin.",
            "job": "I am warlord of Trinsic.",
            "heal": "Superb.",
            "keyword1": "WARL",
            "keyword2": "QUES",
            "answer1": "I have solved many quests!",
            "answer2": "The solving of quests brings ye honor!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Strive ye for honor?",
            "yesanswer": "Then solve quests but attack not non-evil creatures, and get not others gold!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 33,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Swindrik",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall wizard.",
            "job": "I cast spells.",
            "heal": "Fully healed.",
            "keyword1": "SPEL",
            "keyword2": "MAND",
            "answer1": "Spells of great power.",
            "answer2": "Ask at the Folley tavern of mandrake.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou cast spells of great power?",
            "yesanswer": "What is the most powerful reagent?",
            "noanswer": "Dost thou know their main ingredient?"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 25,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Winthrop",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A scruffy merchant.",
            "job": "A trade in rumors.",
            "heal": "A bit ragged out.",
            "keyword1": "RUMO",
            "keyword2": "RUNE",
            "answer1": "About what?",
            "answer2": "There is a small child who knew named... Terrin.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know him?",
            "yesanswer": "Ask him of the rune.",
            "noanswer": "Find him and ask of the rune!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 42,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Rigmore",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A strong paladin.",
            "job": "I am the welcomer.",
            "heal": "Extra good.",
            "keyword1": "WELC",
            "keyword2": "HONO",
            "answer1": "Yes, welcome to Trinsic city of honor!",
            "answer2": "Wisdom on the virtue of honor is found throughout this towne.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek this wisdom?",
            "yesanswer": "Enter and find thy path.",
            "noanswer": "This is the wrong place!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 43,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Kline",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A searching paladin!",
            "job": "I seek entry to the shrine of honor!",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "MANT",
            "keyword2": "RUNE",
            "answer1": "The mantra is 'SUMM'.",
            "answer2": "A man named Winthrop knows of the rune!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye the two requirements to enter and use the shrine?",
            "yesanswer": "What are they?",
            "noanswer": "What dost thou think?"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 30,
        "y_pos1": 30,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Terrin",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A cowering child",
            "job": "I ran from the bull!",
            "heal": "Scared!",
            "keyword1": "BULL",
            "keyword2": "RUNE",
            "answer1": "A big one, with long, pointy horns!",
            "answer2": "It is buried in the southwest corner of towne.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Is it gone yet?",
            "yesanswer": "Whew, I thought it would get me!",
            "noanswer": "Save me!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 92,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 42,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 23,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Aristotle",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A dignified paladin.",
            "job": "I search for honor.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "HONO",
            "keyword2": "DIGN",
            "answer1": "Dignity consists not in possessing honors, but in deserving them.",
            "answer2": "Honor no one, but honor itself!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou honorable at all times?",
            "yesanswer": "That is impressive.",
            "noanswer": "Strive to be as such."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sailor Sam",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An ugly sailor.",
            "job": "I sail the the seas of Britannia!",
            "heal": "A bit waterlogged.",
            "keyword1": "SEAS",
            "keyword2": "SEXT",
            "answer1": "My specialty is navigation!",
            "answer2": "Go to the pub in Jhelom and ask of sextants.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Is it thy specialty?",
            "yesanswer": "Good show mate!",
            "noanswer": "Thou must not own a sextant, eh?"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 196,
        "x_pos1": 30,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Skitle",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A bony skeleton",
            "job": "I hail from dungeon deep.",
            "heal": "What do you mean?",
            "keyword1": "DUNG",
            "keyword2": "STON",
            "answer1": "I come from the dungeon 'Shame'!",
            "answer2": "I have seen the purple stone used in the altars of truth and courage!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Ever been there?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "It holds items thou shalt need."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Publius",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A sleepy fighter",
            "job": "I drink a toast to honor!",
            "heal": "Tired.",
            "keyword1": "HONO",
            "keyword2": "NOTH",
            "answer1": "What is left when honor is lost?",
            "answer2": "Right, take honor from me and my life is done!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou strive to live an honorable life?",
            "yesanswer": "Honor gives greatness.",
            "noanswer": "No honor, no meaning!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 30,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Virgil",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mystic wizard.",
            "job": "I create magical fields.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "FIEL",
            "keyword2": "NIGH",
            "answer1": "Poison is my favorite.",
            "answer2": "Nightshade may be found only near lat-J'F\" long-C'O\" only on the darkest of nights!",
            "yesnoquestion": "'tis it thine?",
            "yesanswer": "Bravo!",
            "noanswer": "Well I don't care!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 19,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 1,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 42,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Dupre",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "Handsome fighter",
            "job": "I am towne leader",
            "heal": "Very well.",
            "keyword1": "LEAD",
            "keyword2": "HONO",
            "answer1": "'tis an honor!",
            "answer2": "It gives life meaning!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou try to live honorably?",
            "yesanswer": "It is a constant quest. Honor is like finely polished armour. Without constant care, it will soon tarnish!",
            "noanswer": "Fool!"
        }
    }
]